LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

Highly experienced full-stack web developer with over three years of success in developing, deploying, and optimizing customer-centric applications. Experienced with JavaScript (ES6+), Node.js, React, Angular, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, EC2, and NoSQL/SQL databases. Possesses a strong understanding of server architecture and latency optimization, caching, CI/CD pipeline, API integrations, and UI/UX design.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer | ORBIT SPORTS DATA | Oct 2021 - Present

At Orbit Sports Data, a German-based B2B startup offering real-time data and reporting services through a JSON API feed, I have developed customer match statistics applications and reporting applications for various sports. My efforts resulted in improved user experience and a cross-continental usage of the product, leading to a 40% increase in user adoption and a 65% rise in revenue.

- Developed cross-platform customer match statistics applications using the Angular framework and reporting applications for various sports with React, Redux, and responsive design.
- Applied Jest and Cypress automatic testing tools to reduce manual testing time and improve software quality.
- Developed backend APIs with Node.js and managed and optimized SQL database queries, resulting in a 35% increase in performance.
- Implemented new features and made critical architectural decisions for the product, increasing security and reducing debugging and development time by 60%.
- Developed adapters for B2B integrations, allowing the company to provide reporting services with its infrastructure to multiple third-party clients at once, increasing revenue by 55%.
- Successfully managed server deployment on AWS to ensure low latency and high availability across continents, improving customer satisfaction and loyalty.

Freelance Developer and Designer | Mar 2019 - Oct 2021

- Delivered full-stack web development, web design, and graphic design projects for clients, including PetrossonBygg, Middle East Institute, Hope Center and Le Pont Organization.
- Developed and launched a React-based website for PetrossonBygg and an online gallery for Le Pont.
- Implemented a full-stack application with Trello's REST-API, deployed with Docker containers.
- Delivered a GraphQL Apollo ePortfolio backend with a database versioning system.

Technical Support Volunteer | Humanitarian Relief | Archdiocese of Alexandretta | Aug 2016 – July 2020

- Designed databases utilizing SQL, UML, and DBLC technologies to support the Disaster and Humanitarian Relief program aided by international organizations like Aid to the Church in Need (ACN) Poland.
- Developed a C# application (Excel to VCF Converter) to facilitate quick and easy import of contacts to mobile devices, reducing manual input time.
- Enhanced team's speed from 250 to 1K Aid-Units/hr for a 5-person distribution team, allowing for more efficient distribution of aid.
- Assisted distribution team with database entry and troubleshooting technical issues.

EDUCATION

- University of Aleppo, Computer Engineering, Bachelor, 2023.
- **Projects:** Connect 4 electronic game and a full-stack manual image moderation system that utilizes AI for pre-filtering.

SKILLS

- **Front-End Development:** JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, React Native, styled-components, Bootstrap, Material UI, Firebase, Angular, Svelte.
- Back-End Development: Node.js, Express, ESLint, REST APIs, GraphQL, Apollo, Socket.IO, Git, GitHub, NoSQL/SQL databases, Redis, TypeORM, Docker, Jest, Puppeteer, Design Patterns, PM2, NGINX, EJS, Plesk, Linux, AWS.
- Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Maya.

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent).
- Arabic (Native).